Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Edward G. Wilson Papers, 1906-1991, bulk 1946-1971 RL.00758
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Trip Files Series, 1954-1968, 3 boxes
  - 1964
    - Mar.: India, Pakistan, Tokyo (See also Oversize Box 90) (Box 20)
    - Apr.: Europe (Box 21)
    - June: Europe (Box 21)
    - Oct.: Europe (Box 21)
    - Nov.: Europe (Box 21)
  - 1965
    - Jan.: Far East and Europe (Box 21)
    - July: Europe (Box 21)
    - Nov.: Europe (Box 21)
  - 1966
    - May: Denver and Europe, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - Sept.: London, Beirut, Far East (Box 21)
  - 1967
    - Jan.: Europe (Box 21)
    - Apr.-Dec.: Washington, D.C. (Box 21)
    - May: Montreal (Box 21)
    - Aug.: Montreal (Box 21)
    - Nov.: Europe (Box 21)
  - 1968 June: London, Paris (Box 21)
- Client Files Series, 1947-1971, 6 boxes
  Contains correspondence between Wilson and the managers of individual JWT offices relating to specific clients. The Unilever files contain information about Unilever's house agency, Lintas, and its efforts to develop worldwide advertising principles, as well as specific information about Thompson's business. Other key clients represented in the series include Caltex, the Campbell Soup Company, S.C. Johnson, Kraft, Pan American Airlines, and the Shell Oil Company. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Alberto-Culver, 1963-1966 (Box 21)
  - Burroughs, 1961-1967 (Box 21)
  - Caltex, 1962-1967
    - Corporate, vol. I, 1962-1964 (Box 21)
    - Corporate, vol. II, 1965-1967 (Box 21)
    - Prototype advertising, 1965-1966 (Box 22)
  - Campbell Soup Company, 1958-1964
    - General, 1958-1964 (Box 22)
    - Marketing plan, 1958 (Box 22)
  - Cervecerias (C.C.U.), 1964-1965 (Box 22)
  - Champion Spark Plug Company, 1947-1967 (Box 22)
  - Chesebrough-Ponds ( South Africa), 1962-1965 (Box 22)
  - Chunky Corp., 1967 (Box 22)
  - De Beers, 1962-1966 (Box 22)
  - Eastman Kodak, 1961 (Box 22)
  - Esso, 1961-1966 (Box 22)
  - Findus, 1962-1965 (Box 22)
  - Ford, 1967-1971 (Box 22)
  - International Wool Secretariat, 1962-1965 (Box 23)
  - Kellogg, 1960-1966, 2 folders (Box 23)
  - Kraft, 1963-1966
    - Charges for services, 1963-1965 (Box 23)
    - General, 1963-1966 (Box 23)
  - National Biscuit Company, 1962-1965 (Box 23)
  - Nestle, 1965-1966 (Box 23)
  - New Holland Machine Company, 1965-1966 (Box 23)
  - Pan American, 1962-1968, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - Pepsi-Cola, 1962-1966 (Box 24)
  - RCA, 1959, 1963-1966 (Box 24)
  - Remington Rand, 1958-1966, 2 folders (Box 24)
  - S.C. Johnson, 1962-1965
    - General, 1962-1965 (Box 24)
    - Program, Art USA Now, 1963-1964 (Box 24)
  - Scott Paper Company, 1957 (Box 24)
  - Seven-Up, 1965-1966 (Box 24)
  - Shell Oil Company
    - General, 1964 (Box 24)
    - Response to agency questionnaire, 1960 (Box 25)
  - Unilever
    - Conference on creative advertising, 1962 (Box 25)
    - Europe and miscellaneous, 1965-1967, 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Lintas, 1962-1964 (Box 25)
    - Lux Toilet Soap, 9 Out of 10, 1962-1966, 2 folders (Box 25)
    - Marketing data (K. Hinks), ca. 1960s (Box 25)
    - Marketing Group visit, 1962 (Box 25)
    - Philippines, 1962-1964 (Box 25)
    - Plan for good advertising, 1964 (Box 25)
    - Questionnaire, 1965 (Box 26)
    - South and Central America, 1961-1966 (Box 26)
    - South Africa, 1965 (Box 26)
  - Warner Lambert, 1962-1965 (Box 26)
- Chronological Files Series, 1951-1971 (RESTRICTED), 8 boxes
  Letters and memoranda that reflect the company's routine operations. Arranged chronologically.
  - 1951-1968, index (Box 26)
  - 1951 Jan.-June, 2 folders (Box 26)
  - 1951 July-Dec., 2 folders (Box 27)
  - 1953 Jan.-Sept., 3 folders (Box 27)
  - 1954 Jan.-Dec. (Restricted materials removed), 4 folders (Box 28)
  - 1956 Jan.-1957 Mar. (Restricted materials removed), 5 folders (Box 29)
  - 1957 Apr.-1958 June (Restricted materials removed), 5 folders (Box 30)
  - 1958 July-1959 Sept. (Restricted materials removed), 5 folders (Box 31)
  - 1959 Oct.-1961 Mar. (Restricted materials removed), 6 folders (Box 32)
  - 1961 Apr.-1962 Mar. (Restricted materials removed), 4 folders (Box 33)
  - 1962 Apr.-1963 Mar. (Restricted materials removed), 4 folders (Box 34)
  - 1963 Apr.-Dec. (Restricted materials removed), 4 folders (Box 35)
  - 1963 Oct.-1964 June (Restricted materials removed), 4 folders (Box 36)
  - 1964 Apr.-Dec. (Restricted materials removed), 5 folders (Box 37)
  - 1965 Jan.-May (Restricted materials removed), 4 folders (Box 38)
  - 1965 June-Dec. (Restricted materials removed), 5 folders (Box 39)
  - 1966 Jan.-Sept. (Restricted materials removed), 5 folders (Box 40)
  - 1966 July-1967 June (Restricted materials removed), 6 folders (Box 41)
  - 1967 Apr.-1968 Mar. (Restricted materials removed), 5 folders (Box 42)
  - 1970 Oct.-Dec. (Restricted materials removed) (Box 42)
  - 1971 Jan.-Dec. (Restricted materials removed), 4 folders (Box 43)
- Legal Files Series, 1927-1975 (RESTRICTED), 25 boxes
  Correspondence, reports, and news clippings documenting JWT's legal activities, primarily from the New York office, but other offices are also mentioned. Topics include the stockholder rights, the Profit-Sharing Trust, the transfer of Stanley and Helen Resor's controlling interest in the company, lawsuits that involved JWT, letters of terms for individual clients, compensation and contract disputes with radio and television personalities and their programs, contract negotiations with the Radio Writers Guild and the Television Writers of America, and lists of actors and actresses approved to work during the period of Hollywood blacklisting. Lawsuits represented in the series include Sartoris and Laemmar vs. JWT, in which the former charged the company for forcing them to sell back their stock in 1964. Another lawsuit related to the company's going public is that of Jardine vs. JWT. Both suits provide information about Thompson's efforts to provide incentives to senior management and to finance operations.
  The letters of terms for individual clients contain copies of client agreements and often include internal memoranda, correspondence with the client, Dun & Bradstreet reports, financial statements, and press clippings announcing the acquisition or loss of the account. Major clients represented in the series include the Eisenhower-Nixon presidential campaign of 1952, Ford, the Johns-Manville Corporation, Kellogg, Lever Brothers and Sylvania. Radio and television personalities and programs represented in the series include Fred Allen (1947-1948 only), Edgar Bergen (Charlie McCarthy), the Fred Allen Ford Dealers show, Eastman Kodak and Kodak Family Adventure, Oriental-International Films, James Melton and Ford Motor Company TV advertisements. The Fred Allen materials include clippings that describe the switch of sponsors from Standard Brands to the Ford Dealers Association, as well as Allen's reaction to the popularity of the giveaway beginning in 1947. The name-check lists of Hollywood actors and actresses include clippings and subject files documenting notable cases of blacklisting and libel actions that challenged accusations of communist affiliation, including those of actress Jean Muir and broadcasting personality John Henry Faulk. Arranged alphabetically.
  - General files
    - AAAA Questionnaire, 1968-1970 (Box 43)
    - Advertising controls, 1947 (Box 43)
    - Advertising Council, 1947-1948 (Box 43)
    - Alcoholic beverages, 1936-1949 (Box 43)
    - Annual reports--Legal Department, 1938-1949, 1972-1974, Folders 1-2 of 4 (Box 43)
    - Annual reports--Legal Department, 1938-1949, 1972-1974, Folders 3-4 of 4 (Box 44)
    - Anti-discrimination laws, 1943-1950, 2 folders (Box 44)
    - Art work, 1949 (Box 44)
    - Association of the Bar in New York, 1943-1950 (Box 44)
    - Claims experience, 1939-1946 (Box 44)
    - Clark, Earle, 1941-1985 (Box 44)
    - Company data, 1943 (Box 45)
    - Contracts for officers, 1975 (Box 45)
    - Federal Communications Commission (FCC), network study questionnaire, 1956 (Box 45)
    - Federal Trade Commission (FTC)
      - Fashion Academy of Design, 1949-1953 (Box 45)
      - Northam Warren, 1931-1932 (Box 45)
    - Financial incentives, vol. II, 1951-1960 (See also Oversize Box 90) (Box 45)
    - Kohl, Howard, 1938-1939 (Restricted materials removed) (Box 45)
    - Lea-Vandenberg Act, 1946-1948 (Box 45)
    - Leases, 1946-1959 (Box 45)
    - Legal aspects of advertising, 1958 (Box 45)
    - Legal/ethical standards compliance program, 1975 (Box 45)
    - Letters of resignation, 1960-1968 (Box 45)
    - Radio Corporation of America (RCA) poison pen letter, 1969 (Box 46)
      Concerns an investigation into a string of fictitious press releases that involved RCA and several other corporations and advertising agencies.
    - Resor, Stanley
      - Finances, 1940-1943 (Box 46)
      - Presidential campaign, 1940-1942 (Box 46)
      - Sociological approach to voting problem, 1940 (Box 46)
      - [Standard contracts: see Oversize box 93] (Box 46)
      - Stanley and Helen Resor trusts--indentures and amendments, 1927-1960 (See also Oversize Box 90) (Box 46)
    - Taxes: Revenue Acts of 1943 and 1948, 1943-1950 (Box 46)
  - Blacklisting
    - Former name check lists, 1951-1957 (Box 87)
    - Name check lists
      During the McCarthy era, check lists were compiled of entertainment industry figures--actors, directors, etc.--who were not blacklisted or under investigation for communist affiliation or sympathies.
      - General
        - American Security Council, 1958-1960 and undated (Box 87)
        - Clippings, 1948-1961, 2 folders (Box 87)
          Clippings relating to anti-communism and blacklisting.
        - Education for American Freedom, Inc., 1961 (Box 87)
        - Faulk libel suit, 1962 (Box 87)
          John Henry Faulk, a radio and television personality, was blacklisted based on an article published by Aware, Inc. linking him to a communist conspiracy. Faulk sued for libel and won $3.5 million judgment, believed to be the largest award for libel damages up to that time.
        - Jean Muir incident, 1950-1951 (Box 87)
          Blacklisting of actress Muir.
      - Casting (Box 88)
        - Brillo, 1955 (Box 88)
        - Ford Motor Company, 1957 (Box 88)
        - Kraft Foods Corporation, 1946-1956
          - Correspondence, 1952-1956 (Box 88)
          - John Foster (Kraft Syracuse) files, 1946-1955 (Box 88)
        - Lever Brothers, 1953-1956 (Box 88)
        - Norby Productions, Inc., 1954 & undated (Box 88)
        - Schlitz Playhouse, 1954-1957 (Box 88)
        - Scott Paper Company, 1958 and undated, 2 folders (Box 88)
      - Correspondence
        - General, 1950-1955 (Box 88)
        - Extra copies (sic), 1954-1958 (Box 88)
        - Un-American Activities Committee, 1955-1957 (Box 88)
  - JWT stock (See also Oversize Box 90) (Box 46)
    Issues related to stock ownership. JWT initially issued two forms of common stock--Class A, or voting stock, which entitled the shareholder to vote on company decisions, and Class B which paid dividends but did not include shareholder voting rights.
    - Correspondence
      - 1942-1959 (Box 46)
      - 1968-1974 (Box 46)
    - Public offering, 1968-1975 (Box 46)
    - Recapitalization, 1968 Aug. (Box 46)
    - Resor stock, 1959-1960 (Box 46)
    - Resor stock interests
      - Class A shares, 1960 (Box 47)
      - Class A stock, 1959-1960 (Box 47)
      - Class B stock, 1960 (Box 47)
      - Purchase of Mrs. Resor's class B stock, 1960 (Box 47)
    - Stock incentive plan, 1969 (Box 47)
    - Stock listing brochures, 1969 (Box 47)
    - Stock purchase agreement
      - Vol. I, 1951-1953 (Box 47)
      - Vol. II, 1954-1955 (Box 47)
      - Vol. III, 1954-1955 (Box 47)
    - Underwriting agreement, 1969 (Box 47)
    - Voting stock, correspondence
      - Vol. I, 1951-1956 (Box 47)
      - Vol. II, 1957-1960 (Box 48)
  - Labor matters
    - General, 1945-1955 (See also Oversize Box 90), Folders 1-2 of 3 (Box 48)
    - General, 1945-1955, Folder 3 of 3 (Box 48)
    - American Federation of Musicians, 1940-1949 (Box 48)
    - Puerto Rico NLRB ruling, 1953-1954 (Box 48)
    - Union matters, 1946-1951 (Box 48)
  - Lawsuits
    - Ambook Enterprises vs. JWT, etc., 1972 (Box 48)
    - Barnum vs. JWT, 1975 (Box 48)
    - Farlowe, Arthur C. vs. U.S.A., 1965-1972 (Box 48)
    - Jardine vs. JWT, 1970 (Box 48)
    - Laemmar & Sartoris vs. JWT (See also Oversize Box 90)
      - Briefs and depositions
        - Vol. I, 1969-1971, 2 folders (Box 49)
        - Vol. II, 1971, 2 folders (Box 49)
      - Briefs and reply memorandum, 1972 (Box 49)
      - Correspondence, 1969-1972 (Box 49)
      - Depositions
        - Brundage, Howard D., 1971 (Box 49)
        - Devin, John F., 1971 (Box 49)
        - Jardine, Theodore R., 1971 (Box 49)
        - Laemmar, Jack W., 1971 (Box 49)
        - Litlig, C. Ross, 1971 (Box 50)
        - Parker, Hugh F., 1971 (Box 50)
        - Sartoris, Ada, 1971 (Box 50)
        - Seymour, Dan, 1971 (Box 50)
        - Strouse, Norman H., 1971 (Box 50)
        - Taylor, William C., 1971 (Box 50)
        - Weise, Ward L., 1972 (Box 50)
        - Wilson, Edward G., 1969 (Box 50)
      - Hypothetical conversion of stock, 1971-1972 (Box 50)
      - Post-trial memorandum, 1972 May (Box 50)
      - Parker, Hugh F., 1961-1971 (Restricted materials removed) (Box 50)
      - Salary and financial data
        - Laemmar, Jack, 1971 (Restricted materials removed) (Box 50)
        - Sartoris, Ada, 1971 (Restricted materials removed) (Box 50)
      - Stock repurchase plan, 1963-1971 (Box 50)
      - Strouse, Norman letters, 1965 (Box 50)
      - Supporting documents taken to trial, 1972 May (Box 51)
      - Transcript of proceedings
        - Vol. I, 1972 (Box 51)
        - Vol. II, 1972 (Box 51)
      - Worksheets of stock purchases, 1964-1969 (Box 51)
    - O'Neill, Ryan vs. JWT (Box 51)
    - U.S. vs. AAAA, 1955 (Box 51)
  - Letters of terms
    - Administrative general, 1964-1975 (Box 51)
    - American South African Lines, Inc., 1947 (Box 51)
    - Aquascutum, Ltd., 1954-1956 (Box 51)
    - Association of Casualty and Surety Companies, 1946-1953 (Box 51)
    - Blue Cross public relations, 1945 (Box 51)
    - Bossart Victor, 1957 (Box 51)
    - Chun King Sales, Inc., 1953-1959 (Box 51)
    - Church and Dwight Company, Inc., 1948-1951 (Box 51)
    - Citizens Traffic Safety Board, 1953 (Box 51)
    - Committee for Community Automobile Rates, 1950 (Box 51)
    - Eisenhower-Nixon Campaign, 1952-1953 (Box 51)
    - Elgin National Watch Company, 1956-1961 (Box 51)
    - Famous Flours Company, 1947-1948 (Box 51)
    - Farrell Lines, Inc., 1947-1959 (Box 51)
    - First America Corp., 1958 (Box 51)
    - Folding Paper Box Association of America, 1958-1959 (Box 51)
    - Ford, 1958-1965 (Box 52)
    - Friden, Inc., 1950-1958 (Box 52)
    - Fund for Adult Education, 1953 (Box 52)
    - General Air Conditioning Corp., 1952-1959 (Box 52)
    - Indiana Bell Telephone Company, 1948-1949 (Box 52)
    - Indianapolis & Southeastern Trailways, Inc., 1952-1960 (Box 52)
    - Ironrite, Inc., 1960-1961 (Box 52)
    - Johns-Manville Corp., 1930-1959, 3 folders (Box 52)
    - Kellogg, 1937-1943, 2 folders (Box 52)
    - Kellogg Canada, 1938 (Box 52)
    - Kellogg indemnity correspondence, 1938-1945 (Box 53)
    - Kellogg London, 1938 (Box 53)
    - Lever, 1958-1965 (Box 53)
    - McClatchy Newspaper, Inc., 1944-1957 (Box 53)
    - Mytinger & Casselberry, Inc., 1956-1959 (Box 53)
    - National Association of Investment Companies, 1954 (Box 53)
    - National Outdoor Advertising Company, 1942-1956 (Box 53)
    - New York Central System, 1955-1959 (Box 53)
    - Oneida, Ltd., 1947-1960 (Box 53)
    - Pacific Mills, Inc., 1949-1956 (Box 53)
    - Pharma-Craft Company, 1945-1960 (Box 53)
    - Skol Company, 1938-1945 (Box 53)
    - Stouffer Corp., 1957-1960 (Box 53)
    - Sunset Magazine, 1959 (Box 53)
    - Superior Paper Company, 1958 (Box 53)
    - Sylvania-Corning Nuclear Corp., 1957 (See also Oversize Box 90) (Box 53)
    - Sylvania Electric Products, 1954-1959 (Box 54)
    - Sylvania Mountain View Labs, 1959 (Box 54)
    - Transamerica Corp., 1956-1958 (Box 54)
    - Tuna Research Foundation, 1952-1953 (Box 54)
    - Ward Baking Company, 1941-1959 (Box 54)
    - Wool Bureau, 1949-1959 (Box 54)
    - Yellow Cab Company of California, 1950-1961 (Box 54)
  - Profit-Sharing Trust
    - Amendments
      - 1946-1947 (Box 54)
      - 1959-1969 (Box 54)
    - Brochures, 1953-1971 (Box 54)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1972, 2 folders (Box 54)
    - Financial agreement with staff Members, 1968-1972 (Box 55)
    - Financial statements, 1938-1946, 1968-1972, 3 folders (Box 55)
    - General Fund statements, 1967-1971, 2 folders (Box 55)
    - Investment Committee minutes, 1953-1957 (Box 55)
    - Investment policy, 1966-1969 (Box 55)
    - Minutes, 1952-1967 (Box 56)
    - Performance, 1955-1961 (Box 56)
    - Phases in the investment history of the JWT Profit-Sharing Trust, 1968-1976 (Box 56)
    - Public offering of stock, 1969 (Box 56)
    - Retirement trust, 1967-1976 (Box 56)
    - Trust agreement, 1947-1948, 1950-1955, 1971-1973, 3 folders (Box 56)
  - Radio
    - Productions
      - Edgar Bergen Standard Brands show, 1941-1942 (See also Oversize Box 90) (Box 56)
      - Fred Allen Ford Dealers show (Box 57)
        - Bond against give-away shows, 1948 (Box 57)
        - Correspondence
          - Vol. I, 1947 (Box 57)
          - Vol. II, 1947-1958 (Box 57)
        - Delmar, Kenny, contracts, 1947-1949 (Box 57)
        - Estimates and orders, 1947-1949 (Box 57)
        - FDA field memorandum, 1948-1949 (Box 57)
        - Payments to dealers, 1947-1949 (Box 57)
        - Signed and confirmed documents, 1947-1957 (Box 57)
    - Radio Writers' Guild
      - Clippings, 1940-1947 (Box 58)
      - Consent election, 1948-1951 (Box 58)
      - Contract with networks, 1947-1948 (Box 58)
      - Correspondence, 1947-1954
        - Vol. I, 1947 (Box 58)
        - Vol. II, 1948 Jan. (Box 58)
        - Vol. III, 1948 Feb.-May (Box 58)
        - Vol. IV, 1948 Jan.-Aug. (Box 58)
        - Vol. V, 1948 Sept.-Oct. (Box 58)
        - Vol. VI, 1948 Nov.-1949 Jan., Folder 1 0f 2 (Box 58)
        - Vol. VI, 1948 Nov.-1949 Jan. (continued), Folder 2 0f 2 (Box 59)
        - Vol. VII, 1949 Feb.-July, 2 folders (Box 59)
        - Vol. VIII, 1949 Aug.-1950 July (Box 59)
        - Vol. IX, 1950 Aug.-1951 Jan. (Box 59)
        - Vol. X, 1951 Feb.-Apr. (Box 59)
        - Vol. XI, 1951 May-July (Box 59)
        - Vol. XII, 1951 Aug.-1954 Apr. (Box 60)
        - Spencer, A.K. files, 1945 Dec.-1946 Oct., 2 folders (Box 60)
      - Independent package producers, 1949 (Box 60)
      - Lists of freelance writers, 1946-1950 (Box 60)
      - Printed materials, 1947-1949 (Box 60)
      - Miscellaneous and general material, vol. 1-2, 1947-1954, 2 folders (Box 60)
  - Television
    - Correspondence (Box 61)
      - Vol. I, 1944-1948 (Restricted materials removed), 2 folders (Box 61)
      - Vol. II, 1949 Jan.-June (Box 61)
      - Vol. III, 1949 July-Oct. (Box 61)
    - Eastman Kodak
      - Correspondence ( Richard de Rochemont's files), 1953-1954 (Box 61)
      - J.K. McEldowney Correspondence, 1952-1954 (Restricted materials removed) (Box 61)
      - Kodak Family Adventure, 1952-1954
        - Client correspondence, 1952-1954 (Box 61)
        - Correspondence, 1953-1954 (Box 62)
        - Reports and news, 1953-1954 (Box 62)
      - Oriental-International Films, 1953-1959
        - Contract, vol. I, 1953 (Box 62)
        - Contract, vol. II, 1953 (Box 62)
        - Contract data, 1953 (Restricted materials removed) (Box 62)
        - Correspondence
          - Vol. I, 1948-1953 Apr. (Restricted materials removed) (Box 62)
          - Vol. II, 1953 May-Dec. (Restricted materials removed), 2 folders (Box 62)
          - Vol. III, 1954-1956 (Restricted materials removed), 2 folders (Box 63)
          - Vol. IV, 1958-1959 (Restricted materials removed), 2 folders (Box 63)
    - Facilities
      - NBC, 1946-1950 (Restricted materials removed), 2 folders (Box 63)
      - Others, 1948-1952, Folders 1-2 of 3 (Box 63)
      - Others, 1948-1952 (Restricted materials removed) (continued), Folder 3 of 3 (Box 64)
    - Ford Motor Company, James Melton package, 1951-1952 (Restricted materials removed; see also Oversize Box 90)
      - Advertisements, 1951-1952 (Box 64)
      - Correspondence
        - Vol. I, 1951 (Box 64)
        - Vol. II, 1951 (Box 64)
        - Vol. III, 1951 (Box 64)
        - Vol. IV, 1951-1952 (Box 64)
        - Vol. V, 1951-1952 (Box 64)
    - Screen Publicists Guild, 1949-1950 (Box 64)
    - Television Authority (TVA)
      - Code, 1950-1952, 2 folders (Box 64)
      - Negotiations, 1950-1951, 2 folders (Box 65)
    - Television Writers of America
      - Correspondence, 1951-1954 (Box 65)
      - Film negotiations, 1952-1953 (Box 65)
      - National Labor Relations Board, 1953 (See also Oversize Box 90) (Box 65)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1953-1954 (Box 65)
  - Trademarks
    - Correspondence, 1940-1949, 3 folders (Box 65)
    - People magazine, 1936-1957 (Box 65)
- Subject Files Series, 1939-1975, 10 boxes
  Reports, correspondence, articles, speeches, company statements and printed materials comprising Wilson's office files. Topics include agent-client relationships, employee evaluation and recruitment, regional managers' meetings, and client records, especially for the Eastman Kodak Company, the Ford Motor Company and the Scott Paper Company. Wilson solicited descriptions of a typical day in an international office, which are included in this series. The run of files for the Managers' Meetings (1959-1970) does not include the 1965 European manager's meeting in Milan, Italy, during which Tom Sutton was named as Wilson's successor as head of international operations. Arranged alphabetically.
  - Account changes (international), 1963-1964 (Box 65)
  - Advertising and women, 1975 (Box 65)
  - Agency-client relationships (Box 66)
    - Vol. I, 1929-1963 (Box 66)
    - Vol. II, 1957-1971 (Box 66)
  - Agency compensation
    - Commission vs. fee, 1956-1970 (Box 66)
    - Commission vs. fee ( Shell-Ogilvy), 1960-1965 (Box 66)
    - General, 1955-1970, 3 folders (Box 66)
  - Agency practice and structure, 1947-1970 (Box 66)
  - American Association of Advertising Agencies (AAAA) (Box 67)
    - Agency service standards, 1956 (Box 67)
    - Analysis of agency costs, 1970 (Box 67)
    - Annual meetings and conferences, 1949-1970 (Box 67)
    - Committee of the Board on Government, 1970-1971 (Box 67)
    - Labor Subcommittee, 1953-1954 (Box 67)
    - Objectionable advertising, 1952-1966 (Box 67)
  - Art awards, 1967 (Box 67)
  - Better Business Bureau
    - Advertisements and brochures, 1967-1969 (Box 67)
    - Clippings, 1967-1969 (Box 67)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1969 (Box 67)
    - Minutes of meetings, 1967-1969 (Box 67)
    - New letters, 1968-1969 (Box 67)
    - Personnel (contact lists), ca. 1969 (Box 67)
    - Reports, 1967-1969 (Box 68)
    - Solicitation, 1969 (Box 68)
  - Board of Directors meeting, 1972 (Box 68)
  - Case for Advertising, 1975 (Box 68)
  - Chicago office
    - International Department, 1964 (Box 68)
    - Office move, 1964 (Box 68)
  - Cole & Weber, Inc. (possible merger), 1958-1961 (Box 68)
  - Company Fund, merit scholarship, 1969 (Box 68)
  - Corporate public relations, 1968 (Box 68)
  - Dun & Bradstreet report, 1967-1970 (Box 68)
  - Ethikos (later Deltakos), 1968-1969 (Box 68)
  - European annual marketing report, 1970 (Box 68)
  - European managers' meetings
    - 1959-1961, 2 folders (Box 68)
    - 1962-1964 May, 3 folders (Box 69)
    - 1964 Aug.
      - Opening talk (Box 69)
      - Planning (Box 69)
      - Working documents (Box 69)
    - 1964 Dec.-1965, 2 folders (Box 69)
    - 1967 (Box 70)
  - Evaluation program, 1965-1970 (Box 70)
  - Exchange visitors program, 1964-1967 (Box 70)